<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Kevin Lloyd | Plantation Shutters Dallas TX</title>
	<atom:link href="/author/kevin/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Universal Window Coverings is the largest dealer of O’Hair plantation shutters in Dallas, Ft. Worth and all of the DFW Metroplex. We are “Gold Rated” and have fast delivery. Call us at 214-905-0011.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 18:58:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Get the Look: Antiquing Your Windows</title>
		<link>/get-the-look-antiquing-your-windows/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kevin Lloyd]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 18:58:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faux finishing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plantation shutters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shutters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[windows]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1360</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Creating an antique look for your home can be done in a variety of ways through the use of color, texture, and décor. One of the most important aspects of an antique home is the windows, because they tend to stand out as the “face” of a home and therefore are one of the first [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Creating an antique look for your home can be done in a variety of ways through the use of color, texture, and décor. One of the most important aspects of an antique home is the windows, because they tend to stand out as the “face” of a home and therefore are one of the first things typically noticed by passersby. Luckily, you don’t have to hire a consultant or contractor in order to get the look you’re after. Modernize suggests making the following easy changes to create a unique antique look that is sure to stand out from the crowd:</p>
<p>Apply Some Window Film</p>
<p>A great way to antique your windows is to apply some window film to each one of them. Most window film comes with a tint that helps block harmful UV rays from entering your home and fading your walls, counters, furniture, and flooring. While a variety of modern and eclectic designs are available, you will find many options made to create an antique look and feel for your home—consider stained glass, faded glass, or scratched glass varieties.</p>
<p>Stress the Window Frames</p>
<p>Another awesome option for antiquing your windows is to make their frames look distressed by painting them in a fresh coat and then using a crumbled piece of paper or a rough sponge to rub the paint in up and down strokes just before it fully dries. When it’s ready to be distressed, the paint should be dry to your light touch yet smudgeable when a little elbow grease is used. When wiping the almost dry paint, use such a light touch so that you can barely feel your hand against the frame. Otherwise you may end up with large smudges that look sloppy as opposed to small streaks that look antique.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.satisfactionthroughchrist.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/window1.jpg">Via Satisfaction Through Christ</a></p>
<p>Install Plantation Shutters</p>
<p>Not only do plantation shutters offer an antique look to take advantage of, but they are typically less costly than drapes and they should also increase the overall value of your home once installed. Plantation shutters are especially helpful in warm areas because they can be positioned in a way that allows air to flow freely without sacrificing shade protection indoors. These shutters are typically custom made to fit the specific window they’ll be installed on, so they can be used on any shape, style, and size of window your home may be sporting.</p>
<p><a href="http://decor.shyblakeman.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/Plantation-Shutters-Lowes.jpg">Via Shy Blakeman</a></p>
<p>These cost effective ideas can be used alone or in combination with one another depending on the overall look and feel you’re going for.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Latest Video on Yelp!</title>
		<link>/latest-video-on-yelp/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kevin Lloyd]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2015 16:57:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Plantation Shutters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plantation shutters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shutter companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shutters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shutters dallas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[windows]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1241</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><script src="http://videoplayer.turnhere.com/player.js?width=640&amp;height=360&amp;embedCode=NqOTQ3dToaw_jx0qYDlP6BN96AK6osCQ&amp;autoplay=0"></script><br />
<noscript><object classid="clsid:D27CDB6E-AE6D-11cf-96B8-444553540000"id="ooyalaPlayer_72c6_gjet6vjx" width="640" height="360"codebase="http://fpdownload.macromedia.com/get/flashplayer/current/swflash.cab"><param name="movie" value="http://videoplayer.turnhere.com/player.swf?embedCode=NqOTQ3dToaw_jx0qYDlP6BN96AK6osCQ=2" /><param name="bgcolor" value="#000000" /><param name="allowScriptAccess" value="always" /><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true" /><param name="flashvars" value="embedType=noscriptObjectTag&#038;embedCode=NqOTQ3dToaw_jx0qYDlP6BN96AK6osCQ&#038;autoplay=0" /><embedsrc="http://videoplayer.turnhere.com/player.swf/player.swf?embedCode=NqOTQ3dToaw_jx0qYDlP6BN96AK6osCQ&#038;version=2"bgcolor="#000000" width="640" height="360"name="ooyalaPlayer_72c6_gjet6vjx" align="middle" play="true"loop="false" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true"type="application/x-shockwave-flash"flashvars="&#038;embedCode=NqOTQ3dToaw_jx0qYDlP6BN96AK6osCQ&#038;autoplay=0"pluginspage="http://www.adobe.com/go/getflashplayer"></embed></object></noscript></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Plantation Shutters Save On Home Energy Costs!</title>
		<link>/plantation-shutters-save-on-home-energy-costs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kevin Lloyd]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2014 18:26:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Plantation Shutters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy efficient windows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy savings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plantation shutters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shutters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shutters dallas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[windows]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1216</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When summer and winter show up to make it too hot or too cold, the windows go down and heating/cooling bills go up. The windows are shut. But are they really closed? Here at Universal Windows we can tell you that it&#8217;s estimated up to 30% of a home&#8217;s energy cost is lost through doors and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When summer and winter show up to make it too hot or too cold, the windows go down and heating/cooling bills go up.</p>
<p>The windows are shut. But are they really closed?</p>
<p>Here at Universal Windows we can tell you that it&#8217;s estimated up to 30% of a home&#8217;s energy cost is lost through doors and windows. That&#8217;s a lot of money disappearing into thin air. One estimate is that if all the homes in America are losing 30% of their energy costs this way, it&#8217;s the equivalent of losing every drop of oil we receive through the Alaska Pipeline every year.</p>
<p>While homeowners look first to proper insulation in the walls and attic, an often overlooked method of reducing home energy costs is the installation of plantation shutters. Highly efficient and aesthetically pleasing, they add an attractive barrier to heat loss in the winter and cooling cost in the summer.</p>
<p>Quality plantation shutters increase the energy efficiency in a home. While shutters can be made with a variety of materials like vinyl or composites, real wood shutters from <a title="O'Hair Shutters" href="http://ohair.com/" target="_blank">O&#8217;Hair</a> are the best. Real wood is a natural insulator and have the best strength-to-weight ratio.</p>
<p>What kind of energy savings can a homeowner expect? &#8220;Quality wood <a title="Universal Window Coverings" href="/" target="_blank">plantation shutters</a> have an R-value between 2.77 and 3.17. R-value measures the degree to which a material can resist heat flow. It&#8217;s estimated that plantation shutters can cut your energy costs by $200 per year or more. That may not sound like much, but everyone can use an extra $200. Especially when that money is in their pocket instead of disappearing in to thin air.</p>
<p>Homeowners appreciate the multiple benefits of O&#8217;Hair plantation shutters. Lisa is a professional artist in Phoenix, Arizona. She purchased her home with plantation shutters in the downstairs living areas. &#8220;At first I liked them for the architectural element they added to my home. Then I realized how practical they were in helping lower my energy costs. Phoenix summers are brutal. We have triple digit heat for months on end. The shutters are very effective at blocking the sun and keeping cool air inside the house.&#8221;</p>
<p>The <a title="Universal Windows" href="/" target="_blank">custom shutters</a> worked so well, Lisa had them installed in the rest of the house. &#8220;Aside from significant energy savings, I love my plantation shutters because they are beautiful to look at and easy to clean. Maybe it&#8217;s the artist in me, but I like the shadows they cast in my home when the sunlight streams in. And that they open on hinges. It&#8217;s nostalgic to me and reminds me of vintage homes of the past.&#8221;</p>
<p>Controlling the amount of light and breeze during more temperate seasons while still maintaining privacy is an advantage of plantation shutters. Lisa laughs, &#8220;Even my dog and cat like the shutters. They both know how to open them when they want to look outside and survey the neighborhood.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Don&#8217;t Throw Your Money Out The Window!</title>
		<link>/dont-throw-your-money-out-the-window/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kevin Lloyd]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2014 22:22:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Plantation Shutters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy efficient windows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy savings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plantation shutters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shutter companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shutters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shutters dallas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[windows]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1205</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When remodeling our homes, we want to save money. The temptation to spend as little as possible is ever present. Overall, frugality is a good approach in life. Yet there are areas where spending less in a remodel today will cost us more later. And later is never a convenient time to make corrections. Because [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When remodeling our homes, we want to save money. The temptation to spend as little as possible is ever present. Overall, frugality is a good approach in life. Yet there are areas where spending less in a remodel today will cost us more later. And later is never a convenient time to make corrections. Because later corrections are expensive corrections.</p>
<p>When it comes to your home remodel, windows are an area where spending more now will cost you less later.</p>
<p>Todd and Brooke live in Lubbock, Texas. They bought a true &#8220;fixer upper&#8221; on the lake. Says Todd, &#8220;With all the things that had to be fixed, a saving grace of our fixer upper house is that the previous owner had installed beautiful vinyl replacement windows. Energy efficient, they open to the inside for easy cleaning. If it hadn&#8217;t been for these windows, we would have passed on the house.&#8221;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Windows are a remodel project where we are wise to spend more than less.</p>
<p>Lori Lynn has designed and built several homes in West Texas. &#8220;The first home I built I went cheap on the windows thinking it wouldn&#8217;t make that big a difference. <a title="Custom Windows" href="/" target="_blank">Custom windows</a> that fit the home would have cost less in the long run because the windows I put in had to be replaced less than ten years later at a much higher price.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>What window material is best?</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The most common materials for windows are vinyl, wood and aluminum. Vinyl is a great choice as they are much easier to fit. Vinyl windows can now be ordered in a variety of colors and they never have to be sanded or painted because the finish runs through the entire product. They are also resistant to fade from sun damage.</p>
<p>Wood window frames add a warmer look to your home and a more natural feel to your environment. Yet they require the most maintenance. Susceptible to fade and sun damage on the exterior, they require regular painting or finishing. Caulking around window seals must also be replaced when it hardens and cracks. Because they expand and contract with changes in the weather, wood windows are much less forgiving on installation. If you choose wood frames, it&#8217;s worth spending the money for a windows professional to install them for you.</p>
<p>Aluminum window frames are the least desirable as they are the most difficult to fit and are most likely to have gaps. Given that up to 30% of home energy costs leak out through windows and doors, it&#8217;s worth the extra money to install windows that will last and save you money in the long run. Not to mention increase your resale value. The vinyl replacement windows that came with our fixer upper added about $15,000 to the value of our home.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Don&#8217;t forget the inside!</strong></p>
<p>When it comes to windows, don&#8217;t forget the inside. <a title="Plantation shutters" href="/" target="_blank">Plantation shutters</a> add unique architectural elements that set your home interior apart. More timeless than conventional window treatments, studies show plantation shutters can save you up to several hundred dollars a year in home energy costs by keeping cool air inside during the summer and warm air inside during the winter.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>New video shows what kind of shutters you can expect for $16.50/sq. ft.</title>
		<link>/new-video-shows-what-kind-of-shutters-you-can-expect-for-16-50sq-ft/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kevin Lloyd]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2013 23:28:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Plantation Shutters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cheap shutters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[discount shutters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plantation shutters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shutter companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shutters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shutters dallas]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=932</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Just posted a new video depicting a case study of a cheap shutter job. Remember the Seinfeld where George&#8217;s girlfriend had the botched nose-job and he couldn&#8217;t look at her?? Well, this was worse!]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Just posted a new video depicting a case study of a cheap shutter job. Remember the Seinfeld where George&#8217;s girlfriend had the botched nose-job and he couldn&#8217;t look at her?? Well, this was worse!</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" width="1080" height="810" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZaC3BdQehec?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>O&#8217;Hair Shutters Introduces Exterior Plantation Shutters</title>
		<link>/ohair-shutters-introduces-exterior-plantation-shutters/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kevin Lloyd]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2012 22:19:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Exterior Shutters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plantation Shutters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exterior shutters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[o'hair exteriors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shutters dallas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wood shutters]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=790</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[O&#8217;Hair Shutters™ introduced their latest product recently- a plantation shutter constructed entirely of heat treated lumber! The heat treating process cooks all of the natural sugars out of the wood making it inedible to insects and fungi and almost impervious to water! One cool side-effect is that the wood becomes a chocolate brown so that [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>O&#8217;Hair Shutters<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> introduced their latest product recently- a plantation shutter constructed entirely of heat treated lumber! The heat treating process cooks all of the natural sugars out of the wood making it inedible to insects and fungi and almost impervious to water! One cool side-effect is that the wood becomes a chocolate brown so that when coated with a sealer, it becomes a rich mahogany color. This will make a great addition to outdoor kitchens and patios. More info to come soon!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Universal Window Coverings Debuts its Consumer&#8217;s Guide</title>
		<link>/universal-window-coverings-debuts-its-consumers-guide/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kevin Lloyd]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2012 16:25:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Plantation Shutters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best shutters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consumers guide for plantation shutters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[differences of shutters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[imported shutters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plantation shutters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[poly shutters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shutters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shutters dallas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wood shutters]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=601</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Everything you didn&#8217;t know you didn&#8217;t know about shutters! No excuse now for buying junky window coverings- this little booklet shows you everything to ask and/or look for in your quest for good quality and value in plantation shutters. Click the link below to see the press release. Universal Window Coverings Debuts its Consumer&#8217;s Guide [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>Everything you didn&#8217;t know you <em>didn&#8217;t know</em> about shutters! No excuse now for buying junky window coverings- this little booklet shows you everything to ask and/or look for in your quest for good quality and value in plantation shutters. Click the link below to see the press release.</div>
<div>
<div><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-647" title="shutterguide" src="/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/shutterguide-223x300.jpg" alt="" width="223" height="300" /><a href="http://www.prlog.org/11919645-universal-window-coverings-debuts-its-consumers-guide.html"><br />
Universal Window Coverings Debuts its Consumer&#8217;s Guide</a></div>
<div></div>
<div>
<div>Potential buyers should delay their shutter purchase until after they&#8217;ve had a chance to read this free guide.</div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
